《老友记》 前情提要
Previously on Friends:
你居然不能去  是啊
I can't believe you won't be there. I know.
为什么不能请两天假
Why can't you take a couple of days off?
我不行  这是我的婚礼
Because I can't. This is my wedding.
真想赶快看到婚礼场地  她父母就在那里结婚
So,I can't wait to see this place you're getting married! Emily's parents got married here.
你绝对没看过那么美的房子  就在
It really is the most lovely building you'll ever see. It's right over...
天哪
Oh, my God!
我只知道延期是不可能的
The only thing I understand is postponing is not an option.
我跟你讲  我们不会结婚了
I tell you, this wedding is not gonna happen.
要是你不喜欢  我们就改地点  改时间  真的没关系
If you don't love this, then we'll do it any other place or any other time. Really, it's fine.
这样很完美
It's perfect.
我要去伦敦  什么
I'm going to London. What?
有人说 "我愿意" 才算结束
It's not over until someone says, "I do."
我愿意  我愿意  我愿意
I do! I do! I do!
瑞秋  不
Rachel, no!
华森公馆
The Waltham residence.
是艾蜜莉的父母家吗
Hi, is this Emily's parents' house?
我是管家
This is the housekeeper speaking.
还有  小姐  讲电话不能这样讲
And, by the way, that is not how one addresses a person on the telephone.
先表明身份
First one identifies oneself...
再请你想找的人过来
...and then asks for the person with whom one wishes to speak.
我是菲比布非
Um, this is Phoebe Buffay.
我是想麻烦你
I was wondering, please...
如果不是很麻烦的话
...if it's not too much trouble, please...
我能和艾蜜莉华森小姐通话吗
...um, might I speak with Miss Emily Waltham, please?
华森小姐去排练餐会了
Miss Waltham is at the rehearsal dinner.
嘲弄别人的口音是不礼貌的  再见
And it is not polite to make fun of people. Goodbye.
不  我会有礼貌  我发誓
No, no! I'll be nice, I swear.
可以把电话给我吗
Could you just give me their number?
我恐怕没有权利泄露这个信息
I'm afraid I'm not at liberty to divulge that information.
有人正要去破坏婚礼  我得警告他们
Ok, somebody is on their way to ruin wedding okay. And I have to warn somebody,
你不给我号码  我就杀到伦敦
alright. So if you don't give me that number then I'm going to come over there...
把你一脚瑞到新咕噜肯夏去
...and I'll kick your snooty ass all the way to New Gloukenshire!
喂  喂
Hello? Hello? Oh!
她知道我说到做到
Ooh, she knew I could kick her ass.
老友记  第四季  第24集  罗斯的婚礼（下）
Friends  S04E24  The One With Ross's Wedding Parts II
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
（插曲餐厅）
乖儿子
Hi, sweetheart.
妈  爸
Mom, Dad.
抱歉迟到了
Oh, sorry, we're late.
是我不好   我坚持要坐那个铁管子
My fault. I insisted on riding the tube.
茱蒂   孩子都在
Judy, the kids!
杰克  那是地铁的俗称
Jack, that's what they call the subway.
我以为…
Ohh, I thought that you....
老爸  老爸  我们懂
Dad, dad. We got it!! We Got It!!!
我爸和继母来了
Oh! Here comes my dad and stepmom.
伯父  伯母
Mr. And Mrs. Geller.
这是史帝芬…
This is Steven...
和安瑞亚华森
...and Andrea Waltham.
你们好  幸会
How do you do? Very nice to meet you.
老婆  是盖勒家的人
Ha, ha! Eh, darling, the Gellers.
老婆  是亲家
Darling, it's the Gellers.
她只想着自己  早知道  不该娶她的
She's very self-absorbed, you know. I should never have married her.
你说什么  是盖勒家的人
Sorry, what? It's the Gellers.
在哪里   这是其中一个  那是另外一个
Where? That's one and that's another one.
很高兴认识你们
Lovely to meet you.
谢谢你们愿意出一半的钱
Terribly nice of you to offer to pay for half the wedding.
管它什么习俗  这是规矩  我们很乐意出
Ohh forget it. Too hell with tradition, We're happy to do it.
我们知道结个婚要花多少钱
Oh, we know how expensive weddings can be.
而且以后可能就没机会了
Besides, this may be the only wedding we get to throw.
真是个世界通行的笑话
Ha ha, a joke that's funny in all countries.
您要吗
Sir?
里面包的什么  羊酪  水田芥和义式培根
What's in it? Goat cheese, watercress and pancetta.
这能吃吗
That's not food.
不  我才不要
No, I don't want it.
这里的东西都不一样  我想回家了
Everything's different here. I want to go home.
我想念我的家人  想念咖啡馆
I miss my family, I miss the coffee house.
我连菲比的长相都快忘了
I can't even remember what Phoebe looks like.
我们才来三天
Joey, it's been three days.
你只是想家了
Okay, you're just a little homesick.
放轻松   好好玩就对了
Okay. Would you just try to relax and just enjoy yourself?
连你都变了
You're different here too.
你在英国变得好坏
You're mean in England!
搞什么
What the hell?
怎么了  老爸
What's up, Dad?
我的这份婚礼帐单  太扯淡了
This bill for my half of the wedding. it's insane.
怎么会这么贵  请客是在家里请的
How could it be so much? The reception's at their house.
花   酒   一楼重铺地毯
Flowers, liquor. Re-carpet first floor?
新的客用浴室  造景
New guest bath, landscaping.
我在出钱不是让他们装修房子的
I'm paying to remodel this guys house.
我要把那个混蛋骂一顿
I'll give that son of a bitch a piece of my mind.
爸   别激动
Dad, dad, please.
我不想让艾蜜莉今晚不开心
Look I don't want anything to upset Emily tonight.
这两天她已经够心烦的了
Alright, She's had a hard enough couple of days as it is.
给我  给我  我去跟他谈
Now here, here, let me go talk to him, okay?
告诉他谁也别想占盖勒家的便宜
And you tell him no one takes advantage of the Gellers.
杰克
Ooh, Jack.
有时候我都忘了你多有男子汉气概的
Sometimes I forget how powerful you can be.
我要去喝个烂醉
And I'm going to go get drunk.
你好  你好
Hi. Hello.
你好
Hello.
下一航班什么时候飞伦敦
Um, when is your next flight to London?
半小时后有一班
There's one leaving in 30 minutes. Oh!
还剩一个空位
And I do have one seat left.
谢谢你
Oh, thank you, thank you.
临时票的价钱是2700元
The last-minute fare on this ticket is $2700.
我的信用卡额度不够
Ugh. I just don't think I have enough left on my credit card.
你可以分两张刷
Well you can split it with another credit card.
五张可以吗
Okay, how about five?
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
请出示护照
I'm just going to need to see your passport.
我没带  不过我可以告诉你  它就在我的床头柜上
Okay, you know what? I don't have it, but I can tell you exactly where it is on my night stand,
这样吧  我有驾照
and...okay. But you know what? I have my driver's license.
还有一张20元钞票
And I have a 20.
听着  我爸不会付内建烤炉的钱
Look, Face it, my father is not gonna pay for the built-in barbecue.
还有  凉亭也免谈
And believe me, you can kiss your gazebo goodbye.
我或许能付钱帮你铺新的草坪
Now I might be able to get you the new lawn.
不过  你得把草坪上的装饰品给我们
Ah! Then you have to give us the lawn ornaments.
我要是答应了  会被我爸笑死
I go back there with lawn ornaments, he'll laugh in my face.
史帝芬  你说句话好吗
Will you say something, Steven?
别对我这么不客气
Don't take that tone with me.
好吧  随你
All right, you can.
菲比  谢天谢地
Hi, Pheebs. Oh, thank God!
你终于回心转意了
Oh, you changed your mind. Ugh!
你现在或许想静一静  现在不想谈这件事情
Oh, look I know you probably want to be alone, and you don't want to talk about it,
没关系  我是想让你知道  你这么做是对的
that's fine. I just want you to know, I think you are doing the right thing and...
再见  等等  你要去哪里
Bye, Pheebs. Wait!! Where are you going?
你又想干什么  等等
What are you doing? No, wait.
为什么她老是在我怀孕的时候这么干
Why am I always pregnant when she does that?
我想敬罗斯和艾蜜莉一杯
I'd like to toast Ross and Emily.
当然  我明天婚礼上会正式敬酒
Of course, my big toast will be tomorrow at the wedding,
这里也就是随便敬敬
so this is kind of my little toast, or Melba toast, if you will.
我跟罗斯认识很久了  他第一次交女朋友我都知道
Okay. I known Ross for a long time. In fact, I knew him when he was going out with his first girlfriend.
我以为他们很顺利  直到那天他替她充气
And I thought things were going to work out for him..Until the day he over inflated her.
天哪
Oh, dear God!
你好  华森装潢
Hello, Waltham Interiors.
你好  华森太太
Oh! Hi, Mrs. Waltham.
我想找罗斯的伴郎之一  或他妹妹莫妮卡
I need to speak with ether one of the best men, or Ross's sister Monica.
你是谁  我是菲比布非  罗斯最好的朋友之一
Who is this? Oh, Phoebe, one of Ross' best friends.
既然是罗斯的好朋友  怎么没来
If you're Ross' friend, why aren't you here?
我不能坐飞机  我怀了我弟的孩子
Um, I can't fly. I'm having my brother's babies.
我是在听广播节目吗
Am I on the radio?
不是
No. Um...
我能不能和他们说说  这事情非常非常重要
...can I talk to one of them? It's very very important.
我对你没兴趣了  我要挂了
No, I'm bored of you now. I'm going to cut you off.
很高兴罗斯和艾蜜莉  要在蒙哥马利礼堂结婚
And I'm sure we're all very excited that Ross and Emily are getting married at Montgomery Hall.
我朋友要在 "蒙帝霍尔" 结婚 （霍尔字同礼堂）
I mean to think, my friend getting married in Monty Hall.
拜托  是蒙帝霍尔啊
Oh, come on, Monty Hall!
《一起做个买卖》主持人啊  你们怎么了
Let's Make a Deal. Come on, you people!
算了  当我没说  恭喜  罗斯和艾蜜莉
All right, forget it. Congratulations, Ross and Emily.
伴郎二号  乔伊崔比亚尼
Hey. Best man number two, Joey Tribbiani. Ha, ha.
我没钱德那么会说笑话
I'm not good with the jokes like Chandler here.
我只想说
But, uh...
恭喜这对幸福的新人
I just want to say congratulations to the happy couple.
我在我家乡附近的咖啡馆认识罗斯
I first met Ross in this coffeehouse back home.
家乡
Home.
纽约市
New York City.
在那里大家都认识我
Where everybody knows my name.
总之
Uh, anyway...
我爱你们
...uh, I love you guys.
但我更爱美国
But not as much as I love America.
我们回家了好不好
Can we please go home now?
你要回去了
Are you going home?
我正想进一步认识你
I was hoping to get to know you better.
美人  我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere, sweetheart.
我有笑啊
I was laughing.
有笑出声吗
Out loud?
我不想让别人觉得我很白痴
I didn't want everyone to think I was stupid.
你怎么样
So how are you doing?
我妈快把我逼疯了  但我替罗斯高兴
My mom's driving me crazy. But Ross is getting married! I'm happy.
我不会让任何人扫我的兴
I won't let anything spoil that.
我只想说罗斯真是个好青年
I just want to say that Ross is a wonderful young man.
谢谢  我们都喜欢他
Oh, thanks. We like him. Ha, ha.
天哪  你生他时一定才十几岁吧
My God! You must have been a teenager when you had him.
我绝对不会付钱
There's no way in hell I'm paying for it.
好  我们只差一件事
Look, we're down to just one point.
求你们了  能不能婚礼后再解决
Could we please，maybe just settle it after the wedding.
好  不过我只想说  我绝不付酒窖的钱
All-right fine, but I just want to say, I'm not paying for your wine cellar....
靠美国才没被德国殖民的小人
...You thieving, would be speaking German if it weren't for us, cheap little man.
那家伙醉昏了  你怎么看也不像罗斯的妈
The guy was hammered. okay? There's no way you look like Ross' mother.
那他为什么要这么说  因为他有病
Then why would he say it? Because he's crazy!
之前他还谢谢我  在《铁达尼号》里演得很棒
Okay? He came up to me earlier and thanked me for my very moving performance in Titanic.
我妈说得对  我嫁不出去了
My mother's right. I'll never get married.
这么说就
Ha! You know what, that is...
谁不想要你
Who wouldn't want you?
拜托  我是个儿子30岁的单亲妈妈
Please! I'm a single mom with a 30-year-old son.
我今天要结婚了
I'm getting married today!
早啊  罗斯
Morning. Ross.
我今天要结婚了
I'm getting married today!
没错
Yeah, you are. Woo-hoo!
你觉得他会发现吗
Do you think he knew I was here?
我以前没跟你做过这档事吧
Well I've-I've never done that with you before. Heh.
是  没有
Nope. Ha, ha.
你怎样
So, ahh, how are ya? How ya...How ya..
还好吗
You okay?
很好
Yeah, yeah.
你呢  很好
You? Oh, yes, yes.
你呢
You?
我们问过了
We did you.
那么
Well...
我该走了  好吧  当然
Well...I'd better get going. Oh yea yea, absolutely. Ha, ha.
你能不能不要看
Could you not look?
我才不想看呢
I don't want to look.
（维珍航空）
不好意思  什么事
Uh, uh, excuse me. Yeah.
要是你打算一路敲打到伦敦
If you're planning on doing that the entire flight...
现在就说  我好吃镇静剂
...please tell me now so that I can take a sedative.
要不也给你一颗
Or maybe slip you one.
我只是有点兴奋
It's just, I'm, uh, kind of excited.
我要去伦敦  告诉一个人我爱他
I'm, um, going to London to, uh, tell this guy that I love him.
喂  你死哪去了
Hello. Where the hell have you been?
我没回来睡  我认识了可爱的伴娘  她好
I spent the night out. I met this cute bridesmaid. She is...
我不想听
I don't want to hear about her!
菲比  我最喜欢的还是你
Aw, Pheebs, you know you're still my number one girl.
不  不  出事了  瑞秋跑去伦敦了
No! No, we have an emergency. Okay? Rachel's coming to London.
太好了
Oh, great!
一点也不好  她要去告诉罗斯她爱他
No it's not great. No, she's coming to tell Ross that she loves him.
但是罗斯爱艾蜜莉
But he loves Emily.
我知道
I know that!
你得阻止她  她会破坏婚礼
You have to stop her. She's going to ruin the wedding.
好
Okay.
我该做的都做了
Okay, so I'm done my part, okay.
现在该你负责  我现在没担子了  对吧
It's your responsibility now, The burden is off me, right?
对
Right.
说说那个伴娘吧
So tell me about this girl.
你看见摩妮卡了吗
Hey. Have you seen Monica?
我没有看见摩妮卡
I'm not seeing Monica.
什么  什么
What? What?
我们得找到她
Look, we gotta find her.
菲比说  瑞秋要来向罗斯表白
Phoebe just called! Rachel's coming to tell Ross she loves him.
天哪  没错  所以要找到摩妮卡
Oh, my God. I know. That's why we got to find Monica!!
你知道她在哪里吗  不知道
You know where she is? No, okay?
你在逼问什么  干脆拿灯照我的眼睛算了
What's with the third degree? Why don't you just shine a light in my eyes?
结果我发现我的一切举动
...And so then I realized. All this stuff I had been doing....
向约书亚求婚  骗罗斯说我要忙
...proposing to Joshua, lying to Ross about why I couldn't come to the wedding. ...
都只是一种表达方式
...was all just a way of... Oh! Oh! Oh!
抱歉  可以打断一下吗
Oh, oh oh!! I'm sorry, Can I interrupt?
你真是个很糟糕  很糟糕的人
You know I just want to say that you are a horrible, horrible person.
你说什么
Ehh, Pardon me?
你说你爱这个人  却要去破坏他的大喜之日
You say you love this man, You're about to ruin the happiest day of his life.
我不得不同意你朋友菲比的话
I have to agree with your friend Pheebs.
这是个很糟糕  很糟糕的计划
This is a..this is a...terrible, terrible plan.
但他必须知道我的感受  为什么
But he has to know how I feel. But why?
他爱这个艾蜜莉  你这么做绝对没好处
He loves this...this Emily person. No good can come of this.
我觉得你错了
Well I think you're wrong.
糟糕
Oh, no!
还有  你们当时显然是分手了
And by the way, it seems to be perfectly clear that you were on a break.
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
跟仙境一样
It's like a fairyland.
是啊  很恐怖吧
I know. It's horrible, isn't it?
我好喜欢  希望我的婚礼也能这么美
I love it. I only hope my wedding looks this good.
我觉得  有些话就别接了
Ha! I just hope... You can let some go by.
摩妮卡
Psst. Monica.
好了  我们要开始提防瑞秋了
Alright, we really need to start looking out for Rachel.
我守前门  你守后面那个大洞
I'll cover the front door. You watch that big hole at the back of the building
罗斯那里有钱德看着
and I got Chandler covering Ross.
我干嘛管钱德在哪里
Why would I care where Chandler is? Heh.
你知道…
You know, uh...
有的时候我根本不喜欢钱德
...sometimes I don't even like Chandler.
好
Okay. Heh.
我愿意
I do.
我愿意  我愿意
I do. I do.
没错  第二个比较好
Oh yea, your right. It's the second one.
是吗
Right?
哈罗  乔伊
Hello, Joey.
嘿  费丽西蒂
Hey, Felicity.
我整天都在想你
Um, I thought about you all day.
是吗
Yeah? Ha, ha.
再跟我讲讲纽约的事
Talk New York to me again.
别管纽约了
Forget about it. Heh.
你好吗
How you doing?
没得商量  我们不会付酒窖的钱
There's nothing to discuss. We're not paying for your wine cellar.
你们总得折衷一下
You-you have to meet me in the middle here.
嘿  你再这么逼我  我就踹你的屁股了
Hey, you keep pushing me on this, my foots going to meet the middle of your ass.
怎么了  没事  一切都在掌握中
What's going on? Nothing, nothing. Everything's under control.
你想干一架  是这个意思吗  想干一架
You want a piece of me? Is that what you're saying? You want a piece of me?
够了  够了
Okay! Okay! That's it!!
双方家长  退后
Parents! Parents! Back away!
这是我们的大喜之日
All right, This is our wedding day!
从现在开始  你们给我好好相处
From now on, everyone gets along.
谁再多说一个字
And if I hear one more word...
别想抱孙子
...no grandchildren!
没错
That's right!
好啦
Okay, okay.
抱歉
Sorry, old boy.
Sorry. Sorry.
我用大拇指就能扳倒你
I could kill you with my thumb, you know.
这是怎么回事
What was that about?
只是一些费用上的
It was this disagreement over...
天哪  你真美
My God! You look beautiful.
婚礼前看到新娘  会不吉利的
Oh! You were not meant to see me before the wedding. It's bad luck.
我觉得我们的坏运气都已经过去了
You know what, I think we've had all the bad luck we're going to have.
天哪  瑞秋
My God, heh, Rachel!
你来了  我真不敢相信
You're here. I can't believe it.
发生什么了  你怎么跑来了
What happen? Why are you here?
我只是来
I just came to...
只是来告诉你
I just needed to tell you...
恭喜你
...congratulations.
华森装饰
Waltham Interiors.
华森太太吗  又是我菲比
Mrs. Waltham? It's Phoebe.
我可以跟伴郎之一说话吗  我保证这是最后一次
Yea. Can I please, please, please talk to one of the best men? This is going to be the last time I promise.
有个女生找你
There's a girl on the phone for you.
真好
Oh, great!
喂
Hello?
是菲比
It's Phoebe.
你有堵到瑞秋吗
Did you stop Rachel?
没事  她只有抱抱他而已
but it's okay. She just came in and gave him a hug, that it.
没有破坏什么  没有
Nothing got ruined? No.
太好了
Oh, that's so great!
现在怎么样了
Oh! So, what's going on now?
我正在走红毯
...I'm walking down the aisle.
还在走
Still walking.
我跟罗斯站在一起了
And now I'm at the front with Ross.
是菲比
It's Phoebe!
他看起来很不爽
He looks pretty mad.
我得挂了
Uh, I better go.
不  等一下  拿着让我听
No!! wait, wait, wait!! Hold it up so I can listen.
昨晚的事真是  愚蠢
What we did last night was... Stupid. Hmm.
既夸张又愚蠢
Totally crazy, stupid. Ha, ha.
我们在想什么
What were we thinking? Heh.
我晚上去找你  好吗
I'm coming over tonight though, right?
当然好
Oh, yeah, definitely.
各位亲朋好友
Friends, family...
我们今天齐聚一堂
...we are gathered to celebrate here today ...
庆祝罗斯与艾蜜莉缔结良缘
...the joyous union of Ross and Emily.
愿今朝的幸福
May the happiness of today...
永远与他们同在
...be with them always.
艾蜜莉  跟着我念
Now, Emily, repeat after me.
我  艾蜜莉  我  艾蜜莉
I, Emily. I, Emily.
嫁给你  嫁给你  罗斯  罗斯
Take thee, Ross. Take thee, Ross.
做我合法的丈夫  祸福与共
As my lawfully wedded husband, in sickness and in health...
至死方休
...till death parts us.
做我合法的丈夫  祸福与共
As my lawfully wedded husband, in sickness and in health...
至死方休
...until death parts us.
罗斯
Now, Ross.
跟着我念
Repeat after me.
我  罗斯
I, Ross.
迎娶你  艾蜜莉
Take thee, Emily.
迎娶你  瑞秋
Take thee, Rachel...
艾蜜莉
Emily!
Ha. Emily.
还要继续吗
Shall I go on?